<resources>
    <string name="app_name">WaveReader</string>
    <string name="titlename">WaveReader</string>
    <string name="informationbuttondescr">Information</string>
    <string name="info_sensor_header">Using sensors to record wave data.</string>
    <string name="info_sensor_body">Press Record to get real time wave measurements! By following the NDBC\'s general approach to wave measurements and using Android sensors like the accelerometer and gyroscope, you can estimate wave height, wave period, and wave direction.</string>
    <string name="info_api_header">Using location to get waves data.</string>
    <string name="info_api_body">Entering in a zip code will allow the application to retrieve the zip codes longitude and latitude coordinates. Those coordinates are then used to get wave data from Marine API. Hourly data from the past 24 hours including wave height, wave period, and wave direction is returned.</string>
    <string name="dismiss_text">Dismiss</string>
    <string name="latitude_longitude">Latitude: %1$s, Longitude: %2$s</string>
    <string name="fetch_wave_data_button">Fetch Wave Data</string>
    <string name="enter_zip_code_label">Enter Zip Code</string>
    <string name="search_icon_descr">Search Icon</string>
    <string name="clear_text_descr">Clear Text</string>
    <string name="zip_code_error">Please enter a valid 5 digit zip code</string>
    <string name="error_image_descr">Error</string>
    <string name="loading_failed_text">Loading Failed</string>
    <string name="loading_image_descr">Loading...</string>
    <string name="pause_sensors_button">Pause Sensors</string>
    <string name="record_button">Record</string>
    <string name="calculating_wave_height_title">Calculating Wave Height</string>
    <string name="calculating_wave_height_body">" Wave height is determined by estimating the vertical displacement of the phone using the accelerometer’s Z-axis data. This involves double integrating the vertical acceleration over time."</string>
    <string name="calculating_wave_period_title">Calculating Wave Period</string>
    <string name="calculating_wave_period_body">" Wave period is computed by analyzing the frequency content of the vertical acceleration data. Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) is used to convert the time domain signal into its frequency components."</string>
    <string name="calculating_wave_direction_title">Calculating Wave Direction</string>
    <string name="calculating_wave_direction_body">The wave direction is derived from horizontal acceleration data combined with gyroscope and magnetometer readings. This method blends FFT-based phase difference from horizontal acceleration with a complementary filter that fuses gyroscope and sensor (magnetometer) data.</string>
</resources>